# **Jamie Phelps**

# JUNIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>Website</u> <u>Email</u>

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Determined and enthusiastic go-getter with 14+ years of comprehensive experience working in fast-paced environments and taking responsibility of high-quality outcomes. Currently completing a Full Stack Software Development course following a career change to a more challenging and growing field. Eager to use this knowledge and continue to build on it within the industry, as a self-motivated and technologically minded individual.

### **KEY SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python.
 Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

Libraries: jQuery

Version Control: Heroku, GitHub, Git
 Frameworks: Flask, Django, Bootstrap

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Completion December 2023 Code Institute

Diploma In Full Stack Software Development Credit Rated by The University of West Scotland

Completed June 2014 CadLine

AutoCAD Level 1 Pass

Completed June 2013 CadLine

3D Studio Max Level 1 Pass

Completed June 2010 Worcester Sixth Form College

GCSE Mathematics Grade C

Completed June 2008 Elgar Technology College

GCSE Combine Science Grade B
GCSE English Literature and Language Grade C

## **PORTFOLIO PROJECTS**

**1.** The Campervan Factory – Website for people to look at Campervan conversions.

GitHub: <a href="https://thephelpster.github.io/CI\_PP1\_CF/">https://thephelpster.github.io/CI\_PP1\_CF/</a>

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Balsamiq, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, Favicon.io.

2. Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock – *Interactive game.* 

GitHub: <a href="https://thephelpster.github.io/CI\_PP2\_RPSLS/">https://thephelpster.github.io/CI\_PP2\_RPSLS/</a>

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Balsamiq, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, Favicon.io.

3. Star Trek Battleships – Star Trek themed Battleship game.

GitHub: https://thephelpster.github.io/CI PP2 RPSLS/

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Balsamiq, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, Favicon.io.

**4. Wonderland Tattoo** – *Tattoo Appointment booking site.* 

GitHub: In progress

Technologies Used: HTML5 , CSS, JavaScript, Python.

**5. Project 5** – Completion due December 2023

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Time Student July 2023 – Present

Code Institute

Part-Time Junior Mechanic June 2022 – July 2023

Twinning Garage

Campervan Technician

October 2017 – June 2022

The Campervan Factory

- Assisting the purchase of vans to be converted, ensuring all purchased vans met the company's high standard.
- Having extensive knowledge on the different types of Volkswagen Campervans and company conversion to be able to assist each customer in a unique way to satisfy their specific needs.
- Quality checking campervans in preparation for customer collection, such as testing all aspects of the vehicle and conversion parts. This also included ensuring any special requirements made by the customer were completed.

**Sales Assistant** 

August 2015 – October 2017

Screwfix

- Building relationships with customers and trade clients, knowing the difference between how to treat
  a customer in comparison to a trade client. For example, trade clients need less stock advise but more
  personable interactions than a typical customer.
- Managing stock room to ensure orders are fulfilled safely and efficiently. For example, having heavy items on a lower shelf and frequently purchased items close to the till.

**Junior Manager** 

August 2011 - August 2015

Dunelm

- Liaising with fellow managers and subordinates to achieve daily tasks and ensure the company values are upheld.
- Adapting to changes in circumstances, such as staff sickness and stock promotions, ensuring each member of staff has the right support and tools they need to complete their tasks.
- Working alongside customers to ensure satisfying solutions to their comments or concerns. Feeding any ideas for future improvements back to the corporate team for implementation company wide.

Sales Assistant

August 2009 – August 2011

Dunelm

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- In the process of renovating my 1920's cottage home, including adding network and security upgrades. I have added multiple internet ports in each room and 1-touch Bluetooth light switches along with multiple CCTV cameras including a doorbell camera and set up an intrusion alert for the driveway.
- I am restoring a 1988 Volkswagen Campervan and a 1994 Volkswagen Polo, utilizing AutoCAD drawing software with a 3D printer to make unique upgrade for both vehicles.
- As an avid gamer, I love to improve games and install mods, recently I have started looking into Unity and Unreal engines to build my own simple games.
- Dedicated Star Trek fan and ship collector.

**Link Addresses** 

Linked In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamiemphelps/https://qithub.com/Thephelpster

Website: Email: https://thephelpster.github.io/UCD\_RESUME/mailto:thephelpster1992@gmail.com